<class xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" name="DiscordLobbyMemberHandle" inherits="RefCounted" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
	A [DiscordLobbyMemberHandle] represents the state of a single user in a Lobby.
</brief_description>
	<description>
	The SDK separates lobby membership into two concepts:
- Has the user been added to the lobby by the game developer? If the [DiscordLobbyMemberHandle] exists for a user/lobby pair, then the user has been added to the lobby.
- Does the user have an active game session that is connected to the lobby and will receive any lobby messages? It is possible for a game developer to add a user to a lobby while they are offline. Also users may temporarily disconnect and rejoin later. So the [code]Connected[/code] boolean tells you whether the user is actively connected to the lobby.
Handle objects in the SDK hold a reference both to the underlying data, and to the SDK instance. Changes to the underlying data will generally be available on existing handles objects without having to re-create them. If the SDK instance is destroyed, but you still have a reference to a handle object, note that it will return the default value for all method calls (ie an empty string for methods that return a string).
</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="can_link_lobby">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
			Returns true if the user is allowed to link a channel to this lobby.
			Under the hood this checks if the LobbyMemberFlags::CanLinkLobby flag is set. This flag can only be set via the server API, add_lobby_member The use case for this is for games that want to restrict a lobby so that only the clan/guild/group leader is allowed to manage the linked channel for the lobby.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="connected">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
			Returns true if the user is currently connected to the lobby.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="id">
			<return type="int" />
			<description>
			The user id of the lobby member.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="metadata">
			<return type="Dictionary[String, String]" />
			<description>
			Metadata is a set of string key/value pairs that the game developer can use.
			A common use case may be to store the game's internal user ID for this user so that every member of a lobby knows the discord user ID and the game's internal user ID mapping for each user.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="user">
			<return type="Variant" />
			<description>
			The [DiscordUserHandle] of the lobby member.
			Returns [DiscordUserHandle] or [code]null[/code].
</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>