<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" name="DiscordppLobbyMemberHandle" inherits="RefCounted" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
	</brief_description>
	<description>
         A LobbyMemberHandle represents the state of a single user in a Lobby.
         The SDK separates lobby membership into two concepts: [br]1. Has the user been added to the lobby by the game developer? If the LobbyMemberHandle exists for a user/lobby pair, then the user has been added to the lobby. [br]2. Does the user have an active game session that is connected to the lobby and will receive any lobby messages? It is possible for a game developer to add a user to a lobby while they are offline. Also users may temporarily disconnect and rejoin later. So the `Connected` boolean tells you whether the user is actively connected to the lobby.
         Handle objects in the SDK hold a reference both to the underlying data, and to the SDK instance. Changes to the underlying data will generally be available on existing handles objects without having to re-create them. If the SDK instance is destroyed, but you still have a reference to a handle object, note that it will return the default value for all method calls (ie an empty string for methods that return a string).
        
        Reference: [url]https://discord.com/developers/docs/social-sdk/classdiscordpp_1_1LobbyMemberHandle.html[/url]
    </description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="CanLinkLobby">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="Connected">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="Drop">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="Id">
			<return type="int" />
			<description>
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="Metadata">
			<return type="Dictionary[String, String]" />
			<description>
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="User">
			<return type="Variant" />
			<description>
				Returns [DiscordppUserHandle] or [code]null[/code].
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>
